hello youtube welcome to fix our world
Friday February 7th edition 2020 spring
insurance public and you Joe and Bentley
join us Jonas won't be joining us this
week
I don't think and we can go over what we
took on last week and what the outcome
was you guys got my email right for the
WordPress login like actually fun okay
good you know I didn't usually recheck a
day later be like wait did I actually
send it has a youtube channel coming
that was the other thing that we were I
mean haven't done it yet sounded like we
weren't sure we wanted a YouTube channel
yet so it wasn't super high on that list
but that's pretty easy to create well
whenever we want to it was on the agenda
was like Jubilee sends WordPress to
Bentley and Adriel and Adriel sets up a
YouTube channel so I was just going off
of what that said yeah I typed that in
because I kind of thought we talked
about and then around the end of the
conversation it seems like the yellow
confused on whether that was going to be
in you know an actual action item but I
didn't think it was that important so
but yeah if we want us I guess jublia I
thought as we would go ahead and create
that channel and start putting these
videos on that channel does that sound
right yeah and so someone else this
stream yard because part of the
reasoning is to keep the tech
cooperative separate then the journey
that is emerging on crowd democracy
channel right keep it separate so people
who want to follow the tech cooperative
are following just that right they're
following the board meetings and the
raisins and whatever mastermind groups
or whatever else that involves into and
also so I can have my 20 hours of street
art for idea cafe and one-off
conversations otherwise I'm quite near
the budget for together tech yeah I can
sign up I upgraded my stream yard like
two days ago so it didn't yeah I guess
it made sense
did I do it yeah
I was at you Bentley who added the
workplace Facebook to the agenda
something like facebook or slicin what's
that Yunus or a drill I don't think I
added it was that for last week no it
was on the agenda for this week but
maybe it was yonas you know I haven't
anything this week yeah because I think
so would be weird to talk about it if
he's not here he's the one who suggested
it but I do think Facebook workplace is
more it is free for the amount of people
we have I just don't know what it offers
that a Facebook group doesn't but we
could try it you see I mean our point
isn't to use Facebook to the end of time
it's to use it until something else
emerges that is better right there
within our value you know what all the
features are like what does it offer
that we'd be interested in and that was
I'm like well whoever put it on there
can tell us that but no no so watching a
video and find you know I mean this is
working okay it's just showing up having
a conversation until there's more people
than who want to get involved and we
need to have a place to necessarily take
notes we have the agenda it seems to to
be working however I don't know what
we're doing right like last week I
should have watched the end of last
week's one again to remember where we
left off but I did usually do so Finkel
like last week was a very full week like
we talked for the full hour and it felt
like we were getting stuff done but now
I don't know for who you are
that's just my memory let me just look
back knack and bubble dot IO
drag-and-drop programming it's just that
you yeah it started that sicko bubble
it's pretty cool it seems like a much
like it's harder to use the neck but it
seems a lot like you can do a lot more
with it yeah yeah it's it's um yeah with
that extra power you have extra
complexity and challenge and a steeper
learning curve I was trying to figure
out a good way to get past the costs
it's pretty expensive to like I think it
definitely will get kinds of once the
sort of needs to scale but I think in
the earlier models I wouldn't expect
need anything past the first or second
tier right well something that bends on
how much money you have to invest $30 a
month could be a lot true yeah I mean I
have a I had no problem with spending
you know I think that's also - is that
just one dev at 30 and it's a hundred
and something a month for from two
people but I mean with like with version
control and stuff I wouldn't want to do
to devs yet anyway
I think like you sort of need a system
to manage who's doing what and who's
implementing it and you know like
storyboards and sprints and all that
kind of stuff before you really get into
multiple developers I would think yeah
just just maybe sometimes someone's not
available and someone else can throw
something up there you would I mean
theoretically if if you're just doing
that every once while you could share an
account yeah
just temporarily we do stuff like use a
must-pass you can share a login so like
if I have an account I could share that
with you and then if you know we ever
not want know if you ever don't wanna
share I can just punch share that log
him yeah yeah you have to start 115 a
month for two application editors I say
we should also because like I don't
stream you're already is I'm guessing
hunter wiki election right like that's
why you got it was differ with election
but starting like any time we do spend
money on together tech knowing who spent
it and then what that you know what I
mean for like business expenses so later
if there is ever money that you can get
that pay back right plus maybe I don't
know double the money back or whatever
it happens to be that we've decided it
democratically is fair compensation in
two figure we could also just use the
Hobby version the free version to kind
of play around with feature sets and
what we want to do like look to see if
we could use it for the scheduling
system I haven't checked about their
calendar into their integrations yet I
think they do have some yeah yeah I have
a pretty extensive integration library
most pretty impressed
and like if push comes to shove they
have zapier integration so you can
integrate with almost anything well that
I mean you need to be able to look at 15
calendars and find a date that's
available or something so zapier
wouldn't help and I mean I guess she's
getting all the data into a database and
do searches but yeah I personally like
I'm not too worried about that part of
it yet cuz like I don't plan to share my
calendar with it Oh like I'll tell it
when I'm available and then or like just
have a list of what spots are and then
some tool to you know convert that time
into my little time zone because I just
I mean I'm not sure but you guys I'm
very hesitant to give any apps access to
my personal like calendar email any of
that stuff well when you're when you're
setting it up it could be read-only and
busy free data so that's one of the
permission settings of using Google so
they wouldn't have be able to I mean I
can't imagine I'd share that publicly on
my website so yeah and for me I would
rather not type in all the times because
my schedule is very spotty right no I
could set aside just a couple hours a
couple days a week and see if anyone
happens to yeah like combined I can see
sort of in in later versions I think it
makes sense but to start with like just
having it you know did a duct tape and
and popsicle sticks for perversion where
it's kind of just like you list the
times and you check your own calendar
and see what times are available and and
it most it probably just translated into
your time zone so it makes it a bit
easier so you have to do that every time
and it's prone to error and as we get
more people and that becomes harder
harder to do we figure out okay what
kind of integrations do we want what do
the current users actually what would
you use if we give you you know GTL
integration if it can look at a public
calendar what options are available yeah
I'm just saying it may be easier for me
to do the integration than to type in my
time so I'll do that I'll just I'll just
do it but yeah we'll sees a calendar
mine's always paper because it just
makes
although I need to get one because I
can't keep all of my conversations that
the weekly ones that are scheduled at
the same time or easy but the other ones
I'm getting confused and not knowing
where I am at what time
but yeah I know I would like to say I
mean that's part of the reason how that
individual to see all the conversations
and to be able to follow them and which
ones are available when I'm available
and when I'm available that it can match
me with to your point that's that's not
it maybe because there will be people
that don't have calendars online
calendars and they will want to
participate so the minimum you know we
that's that's a requirement the calendar
integration is is that so the
integration is a nice to have that will
probably become more important over time
as we get users time where you know we
have a number of people say this is too
cumbersome to go through the list of you
know of all the different things I'm
interested in and then compare it to my
calendar at a certain point we say okay
it's now worthwhile to add this feature
people have been asking for it great
course I guess one discusses is the
scheduler still the kind of the first
thing we're hoping for
what's the most powerful thing but in
anything we create like I don't want it
to be created for the three of us like I
want more people involved but at the
same time how do you like how do you
we need conversations on zoom' with a
hundred people to see kind of how that
goes before with with we pick a schedule
right which is I think what we're doing
with the conference that we kind of came
out of with that was last week's project
raising right like bring your project
and let's talk about that and working
through what that looks like then we
kind of have more of an idea of what the
scheduler it looks like but if we are
just have the scheduler I feel like that
would draw more people in because then
they can talk about anything they want
to talk about within the game be space
or whatever you know let's save the
world space as opposed to come talk
about talking about it right like it's
very niche what we're into talking about
and having more broad converse
Asians but it's chicken-and-egg
everything's chicken eggs I got the
people to know what it leads to look
like and without those people we don't
have the funding and we don't have the
capacity and at the same time if we
don't have it how do we schedule those
how do we schedule those conversations
and we can do it but I can't do it like
yet even I can either say I'm available
at this time it's at this time who wants
to come and there that doesn't seem to
work other people put out a doodle poll
like here all the time so then pick one
which I although I can do that that's
not with outside of my capacity it kind
of is because by the time the doodle
poll is done my schedule has changed
what I hate like it's like okay it's
just easier to pick one I can see it as
such a powerful tool that if humanity
has a way to connect on video about a
topic they care about it is the
beginning stage of everything we want to
create and then how do we actually have
ideas come out of there how do we
actually work together how do we have
100 people have a conversation and have
it be effective is like iteration - yes
yes I think the scheduler is important
unless those did did we ask people
whether if we had that they would
participate and describe a rule well we
haven't done that right well part of it
is the problem of describing it right
like you can almost need to have a
conversation to be like here's what a
schedule looks like that's sort of where
my initial plan is just like you know me
Bentley yonis Jubilee anybody else that
sort of like has a project right now
that they're trying to do something with
just just build stuff for us because
stuff for the four of us and then you
know to have that part of the
conversation publicly and emphasize that
in the game be space with you know the
the sup note up if you want to join let
us know and then I think you know and
you get like five ten other projects
involved to me that's kind of the first
version of this application is we list
the projects for each project we weigh
less like what sort of sessions are
available like around okay here's the
meta project here's wiki election here's
a reason score here's the things that
each one is offering and then as well
you live
like each project has requested help in
these areas and then you have people say
here's the skills I have and here's what
I'm interested in showing me what
sessions I can attend them about
projects I can help with and just like
as their bones a version of that as
possible
so I think we're crossing some things so
maybe we need to be more specific
because when I was discussing the
scheduler my thought was this is the
thing that allows a group of a hundred
people to break up into groups of four
or something so it's unrelated to
projects right it's just to discuss on
topics and I don't I think if you're
doing that project sort of thing I don't
think you need that scheduler that is
right I think but I how I'm kind of
visioning it which I'm now getting
straight here at a drill talk is like
yes doing that because I think that is
where became B is is to bring the
project and create the meta project
together and the scheduler is almost my
project for idea cafe right it's almost
the thing I bring and like hey we do
this even though I have no capacity to
actually make it right but to like hold
the space for the power of being able to
have a video conversation with hundred
people or a million people right like to
have the social media platform that
actually helps us create a better world
and whatever nebulous that means right
but like the scheduler is like the first
piece of that and you know reasons for
an wiki election and whatever the issue
is like the scheduler brings people not
people with projects but not really
unless it has a way to market it and a
way to get people there and a way to
sign people up and whereas the projects
coming together theoretically already
bring people with them or not
right like and then those people become
the more mad at people right like if
they're involved in wiki election they
can also be involved and to be clear
that's one of the main reasons that I
think we start with projects because
that seems to be the easiest way to
bring people on because we're all we
we're all interested in this partially
through the lens of our projects I think
that's the the you know the first step
the the easiest gap to bridge is hey
we're doing this meta project thing to
help with our projects publicly anybody
who likes what we're doing and feel free
to join us we do that until we get
problems until we say hey we're trying
to schedule things and there's a hundred
of us and it's a mess cool now we
definitely need scheduler and we have a
hundred people to ask how would you use
it do you need to I wonder in racing you
need this you need that perfect we have
you know our MVP well let's go so the
question then is if the schedulers in
our first project and the Mehta project
project is our first project what does
that actually look like on YouTube right
because not everyone kids is gonna of
course make this this is our board
meeting tonight the motor project
forward to discuss the things that come
up in the theoretical future and as well
as project raising which are us focusing
on one how do we use a YouTube channel
and possibly one or two other things to
create that right a Facebook group of
slack whatever you know somebody that is
creating like if we had a hundred
projects if he had a dozen projects and
we had like five different time slots
throughout the week someone could
probably meet one of them this is our
finance one our marketing one but any of
it is like we need people before we kind
of grow to that point right right now
together tech the meta project is the
three of us the four of us which Jonas
right so which honestly when you could
make this friend like I guess I kind of
did just like cut and paste him in like
I was like you're in he's like I've
never actually had a conversation as
like hey do you want to join he just
keeps joining which is fine that's kind
of part of this is kind of the nebulous
come when you can this space is held for
that the more people that we can hold
this space for the better because then
you don't need to show up right you
don't need to absolutely be here on a
Friday as long as someone can get into
stream yard it's you know you want to
bus can yeah so what is a beta version
of that besides what we already have
going on which is the project raising
and I think at least one of the first
things I'm not sure if it's you know the
single first thing is me Bentley yonus
not sure if you have a project that's
similar enough do you believe but like
start to sort of meet for like the co-op
petition councils or actually talking
specifics about hey how are our projects
you know what similar areas do they
touch on we know how can we sort of
share
plans knowledge skills stuff like that
and start actually doing some of the
meta project like actually talking about
projects and the kinds of answers that
that we'd want have those conversations
publicly where part of the goal is to
either find other projects that would
join or you know I have maybe three
people in the game beat space be like
wait we the three of us have similar
projects can we start doing that and
instead start to actually design the
framework around what we want around
what like what do we think will help our
projects a to help move our projects
forward and be under the hope that
someone else sees that and sees how
their project hits into the fold and new
areas that we might introduce for them
or for new projects one of this the easy
things to do is to put out to the game
be space both on Twitter and on Facebook
a questionnaire that is what is your
project what is the sticking points what
is you know what like maybe like a
questionnaire that we can then turn into
a spreadsheet of hey look these ones
group together and like and then also
one of the questions is do you want to
beam up with other people who are
working in the same sphere to be able to
help each other in a mastermind type
group right that like this is art this
is actually the reason we're giving out
this this questioner is to do this
I think that's worthwhile I think that
like for what I've seen in the current
game a space where seems to be a lot of
like people sort of itching to do
something like they're like hey what are
people actually I've seen at least three
different Pope's where's basically
somebody saying so what are we doing I
know we're talking about stuff but what
actual steps are we making what like you
can tell there's some I think a lot of
it is in my experience people don't deal
with a conceptual well they can't
understand like if you've been living in
it I think a lot of us have come to
different things that the meta projects
needs to do based on the needs that
we've seen in our projects we're like I
saw like okay there's a real need to
figure out well what does it mean to
trust an organization because what
you're left has to have that but that's
a massive conversation to have
and so it's like if that's one spot that
a couple of projects are trying to work
on I think it's well you can actually
ask and say hey does anybody else want
to join a big part of it is just doing
it it's just having the conversations
being as public as possible and sort of
broadcasting those as sort of a teaser
be like hey here's what we're talking
about if you want to have a similar
conversation come on over yeah so it
sounds like we don't need a tool yet
until we talk do we want to go ahead and
just use this space for the meta project
discussion or is that separately sorry
this space being crowd democracy channel
because we've heard discussed that work
you mean this space is an 11 a.m. on
Friday the mainland Fridays yeah yeah
and we can invite other people like that
is the meta project is together check
right now I want to make sure I was that
was in sync yes what it sounds like is
atrial you're gonna create the YouTube
channel yeah and then we can start
having all of those conversations on
there definitely our fix our role Friday
and the project bracings and possibly
any mastermind groups and stuff that you
and my camera stop saying and Bentley -
yeah the you guys are meeting and doing
those ones live and having more of a
conversation about how do we create
sense making projects together right
with like you only yours you on yours
but how do we actually help each other
in that space for trust and marketing
and those things and I would like to put
out to the to the game be group in some
way a questionnaire that is because I
think it's gonna get way more response
is things to get response what is your
project you know give us a MIDI
something explaining it I don't care
whether it's a website or Twitter or
like literally anything and what
category is in right and then hopefully
something along like the pain points
right like what is it you need help with
marketing and finance
brain start like people to work on it
people to use it what stage are you at
right like is it already up and running
are you at the beginning stage are you
like in between those two or you're like
a long way in but you
we don't have one up and running yet and
I guess also your availability in
timezone right even if that we never do
anything with that it's like actually
that's too complicated I can't actually
match you people up but if it's already
there then it's like in space what is it
this MailChimp do that well or do I need
to what do i how do I put this out so I
think I think this would be easiest to
it using Google Forms which would then
automatically put it into a Google
spreadsheet yeah now M won't wondering
the last few times I've seen somebody
post in the game B space like hey what
are we all doing pretty much every time
somebody comes back with a link to the
game B wiki and the project page so I'm
wondering if we want to pre-fill that
sheet with those projects knowing that
we'll have a lot of sort of empty fields
because I don't think it necessarily
says like who owns the project and all
the other stuff involved like do to have
a website do they have different
channels etc but even just to
pre-populate it like a part of the
question being hey people have been
asking about the projects there's the
game B wiki that's not a database so it
is pretty restricted into how you can
use in the kinds of information you can
track so we've started a Google sheet
we've moved everything from that sheet
over here to give it a start so either
if there's a new project that you want
to submit this nam there and go use this
form if you own one of the projects that
did this let's did please contact us
with the information and we can add it
to the day sheet for you is there a way
like this is the scheduler again is
there a way for us to have just a simple
calendar that is in one timezone
probably PST if it's three of us just
two of us are in PST and you you know
add two hours like a simple calendar
that is like here's what's happening
right right now it is fix our world
Friday and Project Racing's at these two
time periods but new things are gonna
come out right new like and
and the link on there but how you
participate in this week's one if you
want to be on video here's how you know
watching it whatever is less important
also zoom conversations right that are
may be recorded but more of the
mastermind type group and then it can be
uploaded to the YouTube channel I think
that's like a really close behind Phase
two where once we have a list of all the
projects we start to say great what are
you all doing and like you know what
other stuff because that's where it gets
a bit harder to track on a sheet because
it you know a single project some might
have had nothing and some might have
four things and so you kind of want to
be able to say like what are you doing
what time at what
so that means are you I'm interested in
and show me everything I could
participate in part of that is what
project it's a part of but then it's
also like what skills are involved in
date and time and oh no absolutely and I
was in my mind I was only thinking for
together tech I was like a calendar for
us that we're like you're invited to you
know I mean if you want to talk finance
it's at this time period like the more
meta project but yes of course people
are gonna have the one-off ones like
wiki elections talking at noon on what
is and I think the tool that we built
for this one of the things is the meta
project is just another project but it's
one of the projects on itself which I
kind of gets weird like whatever list we
have the meta product is probably number
one and then the first iteration of the
tool that we build that out I'll manage
this you know we'll have recent score
and wiki election and everything else
plus the you know together tech and that
will have its own here's you know here's
the website here's this and that and
here's any of the things that you can do
to participate here's the work they need
here's the sessions they have do you
want a brainstorm a bit what I want
these questionnaires what I want this
questionnaire to be like what do I want
to ask them honestly the exact wording
but like the name of your project
yeah what information what are the
columns in that Google spreadsheet if
you're looking at like a spreadsheet of
all Deepti projects what information
would you want to know yeah yeah yes I
didn't get yelling sprays mean who owns
it the website I would say all their
different channels do you have a
Facebook page
you have a YouTube page do you have a
Twitter account all of them yeah do you
have a patriot but like individual
columns for each okay patreon is an
important one that's if people aren't
using that they probably should because
that seems to be one of the better
options there might be one or two for
like things we don't have listed and
then if enough people add if it can be
oh we forgot you know indiegogo or well
or whatever I think um I guess not like
I say the same is crowdfunding right
your crowd which would be like patreon
Kickstarter those kind of things but you
might have all three yeah you might have
it might be an area where like IndieGoGo
and Kickstarter you can do it multiple
times so that might almost fit under the
like things they're doing so if you if
you launch a Kickstarter that becomes a
part of that same thing as like here's
the help that you need here's this oh
you know one of the projects in a space
you're interested in just launched a
crowdfunding campaign could go take a
look if you want or basically figure
letting a game be incubator that is like
very not 100% yes yeah that's unless I
got that phrase in my novel so it's
looking at the at the game be wiki so
yeah they do have this sheet now I I
think when we post it we could say first
of all like I don't know which of us
will have time but I think you're right
Adria would be good to go ahead and take
these projects to put there so one of
the columns would be like the type which
are kind of the headings here so like
eight well and I don't know when we talk
about projects I don't know if we would
include all of these things I wonder if
we don't pre-fill whatever just saying
hey we know this page exists we don't
know who in that page wants to do it we
only have that the project exists so if
you do it by all means you know we're
not asking you to remove the wheel but
nine out of ten questions or things that
we don't already have yeah and and
wiki's support tables so we could also
mention that when we're done we'll take
it out of the Google sheet and put it in
the wiki either you know there's lots of
ways to do that and I'd rather either
link out to it or see if MediaWiki
support
embedding a Google sheet just because
then it's isolated and it's still like
not concurrent editing and the anything
in wikis is it is messy in my experience
and whereas I mean that's that's my yeah
that's my preference I don't know what
the game be wiki people would think
after this phone call I'm jumping on
like an half an hour exactly jumping on
a phone call with people who are talking
about somewhat of a meta project within
game B which is the like media wiki I
don't know if you know what that means
it was like sure I'll come be more into
that conversation is Phil and Phil is
the one who owns the wiki okay I can't
assign monopolize the conversation with
asking questions but I might have more
information
okay they're using it the typical term
media wiki is the open source platform
put out basically by Wikipedia like it's
they're owned by Wikimedia it's owned by
something else where they put that out
and it sort of anybody can use it
yeah yeah yeah they've maybe talk about
that that may also be talked about
adding all the like digital content all
the media right to the wiki yeah because
I think technically that what the wiki
they're on is Wikimedia yeah yeah so
that'll be interesting is that just an
open group having an open meeting there
Julie there's people in the I'm sure do
you want to come I can invite you yeah I
just wonder if is posted in general a
and B or no it's not posted in general
game B but it's in the coffee shop it
changed the coffee shop because there's
a lot of us at this point in time so I
don't know if we're doing breakout
groups they're kind of looking at like
the vision and the purpose of this group
it's I think it's the first time this
previous meeting for this exact purpose
okay and it's a lot of like I guess and
I remember the coffee shop but where
where is that what is that is that a
Facebook group or is that a gym video so
did you have a zoom meeting to talk
about having you know I'm saying
I ended up getting contacted me on
Twitter and Facebook just sayin like hey
we're having this meeting do you want to
come and then it got just and so he's
like he added me to the messenger group
and a bunch of other people got on it as
well and then the zoom meeting is in is
in half an hour
in that cool yeah then if you want to
share a link to that I know a girl has
to not she has like you know work
allocated all my time and I only have
one hour for game B and two hours a week
for together tech so I don't know
already using three this is like a I
don't know it with what is I guess
that's all three of them thank all three
what project crazy tomorrow we're racing
James owns this project which I think
should be interesting because we're in
no way qualified it's like all about
funding and how he needs to make twenty
thousand dollars a month and I have no
idea why he needs $20,000 a month but
figuring that out like is it is not what
you need or do you need resources that
equal that like how much of that is your
payment which we can't really do
anything about right like P needs six
thousand dollars on to live off of
anyway should be interesting to just
yeah this is what the meta project is
about is how do we raise people's
projects how do we find what projects
are the most valuable and put our time
and energy towards them and suggest
they're the ones maybe if people are
good is going to support a patreon they
support these exact patreon right right
so like I had a question about the forum
if you wanted to be contacted no it'll
come to me if it's going to oh the other
questions
so yeah the I'd like I was thinking we'd
group them by the same kind of types
they have on here so they have
infrastructure since making technologies
economics turns
should be incubators met a currency
project meta currency decentralized
networks so I think we could use that as
a drop-down more glance that suggests
those a link in private chat here so I
can just follow it good for I think in
like you know down the road you'll kind
of want multiple because I think a lot
of projects could it gets to multiple
spaces but I think you start with yeah
you just start with a single field you
pick your main category and then maybe
even have another column what we could
just also ask is what they consider
their category what I think Billy's
point is we just take all the options
out of the way keep adding to a pick
list on the forum so that when they're
submitting a project they can choose
from those options mm-hmm and I don't
know I think the is there an option for
other on the Google Forms its usual but
you have to choose other a minute that
separate field to be able to type your
notes yeah we might still want to kind
of do that but we'll see could also
literally just have other as the
category and then we can reach out to
them and get more information you could
just let it be a text box and then just
get listing at the top they can cut your
eyes truth is it several ways might
actually that might not be bad
especially for like the first 20 or 30
and then we can say oh they fit into
these groups and no contact the person
hey we want to merge your hoop in with
that group does that make sense or we
misunderstanding something something
else that might be good for the forum
less for like adding to the Google sheet
and more does for us is like some form
of a are you interested in participating
in together tech or a game be incubator
or something like that
so that when the arrest is like you know
if we have 20 or 30 people great now we
can reach out one-on-one over Facebook
or wherever it'd be like hey you tell
you're interested there's three other
you know projects that are in the same
space as you well what you want to do
yeah as well as one of the questions I
guess it's like where are your pain
points right is it marketing as a trust
is it hold like what are those but also
where you like I need people when do you
need people to work on it or you need
people to use it
right you want jets do you want
customers or do you want members or do
you want more like yes exactly
and that also will help probably drive
like what the next steps for the the
actual real platform and not just a
Google sheet if everybody says did they
need like workers we're like okay that's
maybe one of the things that we can help
with fairly easily assuming that we can
get the workers interested as well but
if you have a list like if you once you
have that list of projects it seems
quite easy to just make something either
an AK or bubble or wherever to say
here's the projects dick and then go in
there and say what they need it and
there's just a list of all the things
did those projects have they need and
then we can start to bother people with
that may creating project raising in to
its own platform
it's very gamzee it's very like hey you
need to have financing we've both like
not just a patreon account but like hey
there's actual people here's investors
who are looking to help save the world
and yes they're not gonna just hand you
money you have to have a viable product
but like hey here are some avenues
here's our pool of money if eventually
that happens right where we're going to
be here's this stipulation we got X
amount or that was the question this is
going to game be but how much do we want
it to be game B or like do we want a
metric is it just your in game B yes you
put your project on here I feel like
that is almost just the line right now
then later when it opens up beyond game
B what is a project we're willing to
raise versus not one that we're willing
to raise right like oh my MLM I've
started selling essential oil yes I
think one of the things that we have to
answer fairly early on and this will
evolve over time is like what are the
values that we kind of a all agree on
and be like a good number of us still
care about so that we can start to
figure out oh we all agree that there
should be no slavery okay so maybe
that's like a core principle but no
projects can violate its you know if
half of us care about environmentalism
okay that's something that we track but
it's not a requirement yeah
you know be able to see okay what is
your environmental what I think like
I've been I've been geeking out over
together tech pretty much since we had
our weekend conversation that spawned my
involvement in this and I'm sort of
seeing like there's the allied projects
where it's you know to start with like
the recent score and and with the
election and so on where it's not being
funded by it it's kind of being used to
launch together pick itself and and
figure things out but an order for a
project to sort of be officially allied
to together tech we need to figure out
what does it need to do what things does
it need to do we'll put things does it
need not to do like MLMs
what key part in there is it that we
don't want a part of or what does it
need to do in order to be under
consideration and then one or more
layers you know deeper than that is if
we actually get funding what would a
project need to look like in order for
us to actually like financially
contribute as ticked it I gather tech
but I think we just need more people
first like more actual projects to say
hey there's 10 or 20 of us now what do
we value what projects do we think you
know should or shouldn't join the fold
and unfortunately that might involve oh
there's you know a pretty game a project
in here that maybe doesn't fit do you
want to fit to a line with our values or
do you want to leave that's up to you
it's just like you know stop working on
your project you don't it's just hey we
all decided that you know in order for
like 90% of the people decided that
we're trying to avoid slavery and for
whatever reason your your project is you
know tied to a supply chain that you you
have no other option as a group what do
we want to do if that person ends up not
being able to participate they still
have their project together that won't
own anything I think until they actually
start to I talk together Tech has money
and actually starts to invest and also
like I think that that'll be a powerful
conversation to showcase because it is
like we're all having these
conversations on slavery right like I
don't mean here talking about it I mean
literally I'm on a computer that's fun
I can't there's no option to not do that
so to make that better is a very kinky
thing but you can't make it perfect
right so like to use less slavery seems
like that's great you're still using
slavery right anyway but but well
together create that because if
someone's like gonna use let's say 20%
slavery light of a computer that's very
game B but at the same time you're still
creating a supply chain that's full of
slavery don't we're owning that and
being transparent on that part of it so
it's like then we can kind of say yeah
we get that there is that we're not
trading what and especially that's an
area where it gets weird Lee gray is
you're like okay if they're still
slavery involved but it's 80% less
slavery that's a pretty marked
improvement like do we want to support
that you might yeah until we actually
get to an option of oh they did it with
no slavery how do they do that okay now
we're gonna push that project I guess
for do we want to use I know we already
said this but do we want to use the wiki
categories or do we want to come up with
our own because I feel like there's I
really think we can use text just just
have them type of what they think their
category is and then we might have like
tooltips with some examples like we can
use the examples from the wiki to be
like was your category for example
education that's making better than it
up but they can tell anything cuz it's
also so that was one of the things was
um what is it even called like so here
they have cooperatives as one of their
own well we are a cooperative but we're
also not a cooperative not actually
incorporated right but it's like what is
your business model like you know I mean
are you a corporation are you a
not-for-profit are you a I don't know
business type like because then you
don't seem to say examples right like
you're kind of cooperative yeah I mean
maybe we keep it like I think almost our
our first goal is to just start a list
so we get at least I would say maybe 20
and then start to have a conversation
with that community on how do we want to
categorize ourselves like how can we
split
what are the groups those three are
for-profit but they're still doing it
ethically these ones are nonprofit these
ones are cooperatives where are the
lines and are all of them mutually
exclusive you might have some where it's
actually you can be both so that becomes
like a checkbox instead of an either/or
like it becomes a checkbox for call the
checkbox for a profit a checkbox for
this and that the other so there's this
TED talk by a woman called Barbara shear
that's like wish obstacle the idea so
you get enough people together
someone says here's my wish she knows my
obstacle almost always there's somebody
else in a group that hasn't answered
that obstacle
partly because like in project raising
its lot easier to find someone else's
obstacle like right associate to theirs
than yours even if you have the exact
same one right so there was something
about like now I'm in the Facebook group
that's based on like I know we talked
about mastermind groups but they
actually have a format for this wish
obstacle of being able to bring together
and saying this is my wishes my obstacle
I feel like that might be a good type
like not necessarily conference but just
a mastermind type group or you bring
together people and say hey my wish is
that wiki like exists my obstacle
is that it doesn't but like something
more concrete than that or a certain
problem you're trying to solve that
could that that can be a westlake and
everyone has five minutes so like you
get together with four other people and
you each have five minutes to deal with
your I see so I I'm guessing it's
probably like a five minute intro the
four people go through and they've been
a five minute conclusion that's it's
half an hour and so that's more what I'm
sorry that yeah and now I'm remembering
when I brought that up that could be
like a conference we do like I don't
keep saying conferences meeting bringing
people and having more than three of us
having like a two-hour Zoo meeting where
people are bringing their projects
giving us a 30 seconds feel and what the
project is and what their greatest
barrier is right and then you know maybe
don't help them fix it we just are kind
of collecting information on that of
like oh okay your biggest one is
marketing and finance and and then from
that putting them into groups of these
people want to talk about finance even
if it's not related right and or these
people have edgy
projects are we matching them based on
their project or on their pain point and
both it like it's where do you want to
be matched and just finding it finding
out that that for an exploratory caddy
exploratory all over the place all right
like my inkling here is that like the
number one goal which I think we all
kind of agreed on is to get other
projects involved I wouldn't even worry
too much about planning past that
because the whole thing is to start
asking them to the kinds of questions
that we have for the next step in the
next step so we can start to have like
oh no we have 20 people to ask we can
start to get a sampling of what do you
think about this this be our
next step if five people are like
actually here's our number one problem
both Bentley and I might say oh actually
I had a problem too okay yeah that's
probably a better one just like trying
to plan out what we think it's gonna be
in two or three iterations when we
probably don't even have 5% of the
people that we need to be involved
before we can move to the next step I
think you can have some general ideas
and like here's our suggestions to kind
of start those conversations once we
have 20 30 50 projects but everything
focuses on just getting those people so
we can start to ask them that these
questions in context when I make the
forum and put out the forum that's fine
they answer it that's there but I guess
that's I guess the call to action is
fill out the form and then it's we pick
a time and put out to them hey who's
available at this time or put our two
doodle poll to these people which times
are you available which one runs the
most times is the one that we look at
here's the structure of the meeting we
can discuss maybe the start for the
meeting in such next time yeah we do
want to make sure we can get in touch
with everybody so I think on the Google
Form there's an option to collect the
emails and that may be the best way
right yeah I that might be kind of a
tight end thing to do you want to
participate in this project mark going
forward or do you just want to be like a
listing you so that if somebody's
looking they can see it and go to your
website or do you want to participate
sort of a step or two more and then that
although I guess if they're gonna be
listed we would need
sort of way to contact them I mean if
they could try yeah I think it's we've
enough they don't want to pretend right
yeah so I think we probably ask for a
can we contact them about this and then
be if so how and then I guess it might
also be clearly gets do you want to
participate in together tech as it is
now you can change your answer going
forward if you don't want you right now
but then in six months you're like oh
they're doing cool stuff sure come on
over it's also that so we have 10 ish
minutes left
can we brainstorm a blur like our
elevator pitch on the meta project like
what is together tech right now so that
it's like why are we looking to fill out
this form because like we want to help
you in your projects right we want to
find how we can just solutions into the
world yeah so I would I would so some of
the phrasings for that I'd be like um we
want to I like saying practice game
because then you kind of get around that
whole thing about well we should be
working on ourselves not on tech so we
want to practice game B and you know
build the tools that we you know as a
group build the tools to facilitate
transition to game be I don't know and
just support everyone who already has a
project because I guess we're our
audiences and the people that don't have
a project one do a project so they might
just don't have if you have a project
that relates to game be read further
otherwise sawed-off yeah because there's
a very related which we're not taking
this path but there's a very related
like there's what's all of our pain
points are for why we're not
participating more in game B and they
are the same it's like well I need a job
I need food I need clothes you know like
I need I need to be able to get my
resources met and
everyone has those pain points and those
are actually more common pain points to
touch but when I put like I said when I
put out like the food one no crickets
nobody like they don't even know that's
an issue so that's why we're focusing on
this one but I think there will be
people who come forward and almost to
give that answer like well my project is
me well no it's not cuz I tried you
didn't answer you didn't want to get fed
you didn't want to figure out your food
source but so yeah I think yeah yeah
saying something to the effect of you
know it's a way to find ways to meet or
I don't know that's a have a job in the
game be space so let's make transition
to game be by co-creating the tools
projects yeah some of the ground like
setting a framework for game B projects
to sort of they actually start being
game being being cooperative because you
know if we want to talk to talk maybe we
should start doing that instead of all
being off in our own silos and then just
like you know once we have that actually
figuring out what do we need to move all
of our projects forward because in
theory our projects are our
interpretation of what's necessary just
in general and possibly what's necessary
for can be and I think like you would if
we're trying to attract people with
projects it's all about the T projects
it's not even about like the amount a
project in this and game B in
cooperative it's just do you want to
work with other project owners both in
general and that have very similar
projects to sort out sort of you know
collaborate and that was to collaborate
with other project people to figure out
how to move your project part
specifically and how to set a framework
for other projects to follow yeah
with yours and if you want to you can
get involved in the meta project and I
know that's what that one which is its
own project which is I think that as it
were like as we have the conversations I
think the the start is just project
owners helping product owners it's like
a really simplified version and you know
it needs some more meat there but
personally I think that we should avoid
even saying that a project or take like
our gym owners cooperating on their
projects operating - yeah I think it's
like a get get help on your project but
then also and this may even be able to
work on that framework so other projects
so we can start to build the rule set
for what helps launch project how do you
get an audience how do you get funding
how do you do like all the questions
that we all have working on answers
together and sort of sharing our results
yeah maybe maybe something as short as
get help on your project and help other
projects yeah you know I do think
there's something very attractive about
this proposal because when I talk to
people even about um project raising
they don't necessarily want to come to
be part of fix our old Friday's they do
want to be part of project raising
either as the project or even to help
other people's projects like yeah that
sounds fun um even if they aren't
available at that time and or don't know
if they have the expertise to
participate and all of that so which is
its own its own problem so thing every
wants our project raised and nobody
wants raise other people's projects it's
an issue but it's an issue that has
arisen and we're figuring it out as we
go we're raising people's projects cuz
we like it they're getting what they get
out of it alright get help on your
project help other people's projects
please this first point fill up the
survey do we want to do I want to also
put in a doodle poll like another like
both of those things at the same time
like also fill out they do a poll for if
you are do you want to get in contacted
for the meta project right to talk about
this framework if yes or do we just
invite them to this next week I think we
just invited them to this yeah and I
would err on the side of if we're trying
to find times like until we can sort of
hit phase two and have a tool for it I
would say just picked three times that
work like for us or for two of us and
then you know here's three or four times
that work please vote on them and then
you know do one that gets the most likes
for uploads forever cool we'll do it
that way and then once that starts to
become really unwieldy we say alright we
need something now it's time to focus on
the scheduling tool I think also if this
isn't like we've had no one here today
if we have more interests like let's say
we have ten people who really want to
get started and for next week we move on
to zoom
we need to zoom account then and I'm
sure I can borrow one just leaving the
coffee shop we can example one of those
ten people want to join this exact
session and have that conversation yeah
yeah I think it's beyond the the stream
yard six-person which is a great problem
to have I'm saying I'm you
I have to solve that problem my own mind
I'll be like no we can only have six oh
now I don't know how to have six
whereas yes if we're okay moving on to
zoom I'm okay with having that problem
and then therefore I would all sort
maybe you've leaning towards it at least
until it becomes even more a problem
like asking people didn't want to join
sort of figuring out what capacity they
are plan around having six people and
then part of it is seeing like as we
also need to sort of practice having an
interactive audience and saying what
what happens as chats come in how does a
conversation work who answers what like
if we're working on that and I think
that also sort of to use a term build a
bit of scarcity and might make it more
interesting you like you wanted to know
to took it in here's your pitch for why
you should be a part of the six on
screen and then if you don't make it
this week cool you might make it next
week you put the topic that you're more
attuned to yeah so also I think that we
need this YouTube channel by next week
no I think starting this on a new
YouTube channel is also good cuz I don't
forget like those will be our
subscribers and having everyone
subscribe to that one and be part of the
comments which means we also have be
able to go live right yeah so probably
what all do is all set up the D chip
channel add it to my my stream yard and
then all share the that login info with
just you for now Jubilee so that will
have two people that can do it and if we
need to I can sure prevent me as well
but the goal is to have as few as few
fingers and that PI as possible yeah
where the was that the YouTube channel
first a stream yard because stream yard
it can string to my personal one to wiki
election and then it'll be able to
stream two together tech as well yeah we
might also because I have now the paid
version I we if we want to we can also
stream to multiple areas at once so we
could stream to you to the Facebook yeah
you know what I think because of that
because you actually have the paid
version and it might be worth setting up
a Facebook account because I feel like
it's going to end people who want to be
involved can because then I also don't
have
to contact people to be like hey if you
want to spit on video collect this
length less like it's it's there right
it's like yeah this is this week's one
come watch it and do it do it that way
I'm not great at having a Facebook group
so I can't do it by myself
but creating that so that there is
somewhere we can go to interact right
because until we get to where game B is
which is a thousand people and it's
getting a little too much now that's a
good that's a great place to be for our
issues people with projects we have a
hundred people with projects interactive
that would be probably going to be well
past the point where we're like well we
need to fix some stuff this is very
unwieldy yeah but it's also like let's
say we don't have our individual
projects we're together tech right so
you might have three people on one
project that are all part of it they
aren't necessarily IP back yeah I'm
we're talking about the number of
projects involved as opposed to cover
people where I'm thinking they'll mostly
be one-to-one to start with but all
right open to being wrong so you're
gonna start the YouTube channel and what
I meant by going live is we have to be
able to go live which means you can't
wait till Friday right like you do have
live issues and then I'm gonna put out
the Facebook group I'm gonna ask people
to be coming to this on Friday after the
I might even kind of almost just do that
because that'll be less of a sticking
point for my brain and then I'll figure
out later by then like as we're sharing
this and as you know at least to start
with it's gonna be wiki election and
together tech there might end up being
more that are sort of having spots
having a calendar of like this for
example I don't think that we can use
String yard if like Saturday's at noon
pacific I'm doing the wiki election last
room so we can't have someone else do it
together tech last room at the same time
even though they're on different
projects yeah that might be hasn't like
a really simple even a you know a Google
sheet in the background where it's just
like a grid of days and times in the
spots that are reserved so if we're
planning new spots were like oh I
shouldn't do that because that's I take
either tech or a wiki election or
etcetera
I think you'll make an open Google
Calendar as well I think we're using
stream yard for fixer rolled Fridays and
raising projects and then what you're
doing with a collection or anything else
that we might do outside of that I think
we use zoom and we record it and I'll
what I just do okay great how do we
figure that out but anyone can write
because then four people could have one
not on string like right and now give it
to me and we'll upload it and deal with
it that way so that it can be on this
channel if you want it to be on this
channel right it's also get like more
subscribers to that channel so that
those subscribers are everybody's
audience right like when you're raising
your project here is our audience to be
able to appraise your project to like we
want different ends up being one of the
appeals of together tech once it gets
going is you don't just get help you
also get exposure to these together pick
audience who's selling them are bound to
be interested in it if there's some
crossover yeah absolutely
all right I got to go and get part of
the next conversation on zoom and am i
sending that to you to Bentley
you're gonna comment yeah okay so let's
say goodbye to YouTube bye YouTube
I know YouTube right